hey folks David Tao with barbend.com and
we have your winners for the 2023 Noble
CrossFit Games on the women's side Laura
Horvath of Hungary comes away with her
first ever games overall Victory she
burst onto the scene in 2018 as a rookie
and finished second she has a few Podium
appearances to her name but this was her
breakthrough year the one that we
thought could really be well poised to
inherit Tia Clair toomey's crown and she
does just that but not without a fight
we'll go into that and on the men's side
we had a lot of drama Jeffrey Adler the
Canadian athlete who's been nipping at
the podium for what seems like years
comes away with the overall Victory and
is the fittest man on Earth but Roman
krenikov who is in the lead heading to
the final day of competition breaks his
foot or reportedly breaks his foot on
one of the events on the day and drops
back to third allowing Adler to secure
the victory we've got all that and more
coming up in this video hey folks a
quick note if you're watching this video
now and you want to stay up to date 8 on
the latest and greatest in CrossFit
strongman powerlifting bodybuilding you
name it it's strength we got it
subscribe to barbin on YouTube let's
break down the winners really quickly in
the women's division men's division and
the team division just to make it clear
in the women's division CrossFit Games
veteran Laura Horvath of Hungary she's
your champion and the fittest woman on
Earth in the men's division Jeffrey
Adler of Canada he's your champion and
the fittest man on Earth in the team
division Crossfit Invictus basically
makes it a wire to wire Victory they're
the fittest team on Earth the women's
Podium is Lara Horvath of Hungary Emma
Lawson of Canada and Arielle lowen of
the United States the men's Podium it's
a lot of Canadians it's Jeffrey Adler of
Canada in first Patrick vellner of
Canada in second we're used to hearing
that name in second or third place of
the CrossFit Games and Roman krenikov
who's from Russia but is not officially
representing Russia due to International
sanctions he finishes in third place
overall Bryn fakowski the professor also
of Canada just outside the top three he
finishes in fourth place so a ton of
Canadian representation they take half
of the individual Podium spots this year
on the team side it really wasn't a
quest who would win all weekend but a
question of what order the podium would
be in Crossfit Invictus takes a victory
CrossFit East Nashville proven finishes
in second place in the team Division and
Crossfit Oslo navy blue finishes in
third place the second and third place
finishers have been kind of
flip-flopping all weekend it was
actually a really tight race to see who
would stand where on the podium there
were three events for individuals on the
day one was muscle up log and it was a
five round series of muscle ups and then
getting a heavy sandbag over a series of
logs this event or at least coming into
this event well Roman krenikov looked
incredibly well poised he was wearing
the leader Jersey he looks strong this
event actually looked really good for
him he's good at some of these classic
CrossFit couplets but here's the deal
Jeffrey Adler was able to gain 87 points
in one event on krenikov and krenikov
unfortunately seemed to be injured
significantly at the end of this event
reportedly he broke his foot or tore
significant ligaments in his foot
basically his foot was not operational
and he was forced to finish the cross
games on one leg and we hate to say that
he was a lock for victory beyond that we
hate to say that he was guaranteed to be
the fittest man on Earth if he hadn't
been hurt we don't know the point is it
really changed things up at the last
possible second in the second to last
event we knew that we were going to see
some shake-ups and that Adler would
probably overtake karenikov it was
pretty crazy it was pretty dramatic
credit card actually came out and did
compete in the 11th event which included
double unders that he was doing on one
foot now there wasn't a minimum work
requirement he wasn't necessarily
required to do this but he did it anyway
and that actually created a lot of
conversation online as to whether
CrossFit should let him cronikov said
that he wanted to set a good example and
be a tenacious competitor through and
through especially for his young son who
was looking on to the competition a lot
of pundits and a lot of discussions in
forums said that criticov shouldn't be
allowed to compete when he was obviously
so injured that he couldn't even bear
weight on one of of his feet it actually
reminds me of years and years ago when
Julie Fouche tore her Achilles heel in
regionals when she was in Prime position
to qualify for the games and then wasn't
able to actually qualify but was able to
finish the workouts on one leg
regardless of my personal opinion or
what folks say about whether or not that
should be allowed it's clear chronikov
has a lengthy path to recovery ahead of
him because this is a pretty significant
injury it's more than just a strain we
don't know all the details but we're
wishing him a speedy recovery well let's
talk about who won event 10 and well
your ultimate winner is it was really
telling for where the momentum went
today Jeffrey Adler of Canada and Laura
Horvath of Hungary They Come Away with
event wins in event 10 and it really
positioned both of them to hold on to
that top Podium spot event number 11 for
the individuals was parallel bar pool
they had to Traverse parallel bars heavy
rope double unders where the ropes a
little heavier than normal and then they
had hand over hand sled drags again
really one of the standout moments here
was karenikov trying to complete this
workout on one foot with those heavy
rope double unders it's an image that's
going to stick into the consciousness of
CrossFit fans for a long time it's
really tough to get that out of our
heads again whether or not you agree
with crossfit's decision to let him go
on in the competition everyone was
behind chronicov on this everyone was
cheering for him it's one of those
things where it really makes you realize
how the sport is so supportive of
individuals these weren't competitors
necessarily in this event no one was
competing against Roman krenikov
everyone was competing for him or
everyone was rooting for him I should
say it was a an immense and an immensely
impressive display of sportsmanship from
all the competitors on the field the
winners ultimately were Brent fakowski
the professor who was really just in
spitting distance of the podium all
weekend but couldn't quite secure one of
those top three spots and again Laura
Horvath of Hungary well she really
extended her lead with this event win
another event win and kind of extended
her lead over Emma Lawson of Canada and
this event was pretty much a coronation
for Horvath at least in my opinion right
the 12th and final event for individuals
at the 2023 CrossFit Games was Echo
Thruster and this looked brutal it was a
descending ladder of calories on the
Echo Bike that's rough in and of itself
and thrusters and though the revs went
down the weight went up and oh yeah they
had to Lunge with the thrusters overhead
or with those barbells overhead this is
a brutal workout and the barbells got
heavy enough at the end to where uh you
know it was a question whether or not
athletes would be able to do things like
those overhead walking lunges unbroken
so again this is classic crossover we've
seen CrossFit in games with things like
Grace or Fran and and this is kind of
right in that element let's put a nasty
couplet there let's make the weights a
little bit heavier something that mere
mortals at home I might want to scale
before they try and let's see how these
top athletes do at the end of four days
of exhausting competition the question
on the men's side coming into this event
wasn't can Jeffrey Adler win the event
it was can he keep enough distance
between him self and his competitors Dal
and pepper actually takes the event win
and finishes in first place but Adler
finishes in fifth place and that's
enough to ensure that he stays on top of
the podium keeps the leaders jersey and
is the 2023 fittest man on Earth so
congratulations to Adler for a great
performance a top five finish on the
final event of the weekend to secure
that top spot really gritty stuff other
names that finished well in this event
on the men's side Samuel Quant who is a
previous Podium finisher and Justin
madiros the two-time defending champion
who ultimately was not able to crack the
top 10 this year after his worst ever
start to the games he finished this
event in third place overall it was
reminiscent of classic Justin Medeiros
and it's going to be interesting to see
how he takes time after the games maybe
reassesses his training we're not sure
if maybe he was dealing with an injury
or some nagging aches and pains coming
into this but we weren't seeing the
Justin Maderos that we saw in 2021 and
2022. that's for sure but it was really
really cool to see him end on a
relatively high note with a top three
event finish at the very end of
competition on the women's side for
event 12 a name we haven't heard a lot
of this weekend and that's Olivia
kerstetter of the United States she
comes away with an event Victory one
thing I want to call out there was
another series of cuts between Saturday
and Sunday for individuals at the
CrossFit game so there were only 20
competitors each in the men's and
women's division so two Heats of 10
athletes each I actually think it
smoothed the viewing experience a little
bit but cuts are a bit controversial and
Brent fakowski actually has some really
good content he's posted on Instagram as
to why he thinks cuts are generally a
bad idea at the games uh we're curious
to see your thoughts on the cut
structure this year so you know let us
know in the comments below please also a
strong finisher on this event on the
women's side Katrin David's daughter the
former two-time champ from Iceland
finished his second place overall in
this event and scores a top 10 finish
she finishes in seventh place overall
she and Annie Thor's Daughter were both
performing pretty well especially on
Thursday and Friday and we were
wondering could Iceland return to the
podium turns out no but it was great
great to see both of these athletes who
have been competing in the sport for
well over a decade each still at the top
of the game and able to hang with the
elite athletes and finish and actually
make it past the cuts to the final day
of competition so congrats to Annie and
Katrin they had a lovely series of
moments they're best friends they were
cheering each other on the competition
floor it's exactly what we want to see
on the team side I want to point out
what it means to finish strong and
that's finishing in first and second on
the final two Events Crossfit Invictus
finished the final two events Bob's a
drag and handstand worm in first and
second place overall they were almost
assured the victory as long as they did
minimum work requirements coming into
the final day of competition really good
to see them finish on a high note and
really signify they are truly wire to
wire the fittest team on Earth this is
probably the most dramatic final day of
competition we've seen at the CrossFit
Games in a long time we knew there was
going to be a new winner on the women's
side because team claritumi isn't
competing for the first time in a long
time and she won six times in a row and
on the men's side well we weren't so
sure Justin Maderos looked to have a
pretty good lock on this he looked
really fit coming in could he earn his
third CrossFit Games title in a row and
it was clear on the first day of
competition that Hugh had an uphill
battle and it became clear heading into
the weekend especially by Saturday that
we were probably going to have a new
men's Champion Jeffrey Adler of Canada
is someone who has put in the work and
has been a consistently top performer
for four or five years at the CrossFit
Games level it's cool to see a Canadian
man stand on top of the podium after
years and years of second and third
place finishes from the likes of Brent
fakowski and Patrick belner and velner
by the way racks up yet another Podium
finish yet another second place is he
the fittest person to never win the
CrossFit Games I think that debate is
pretty much settled he is Patrick
vellner has to be the fittest person to
never win the CrossFit Games there have
been some conversations as to whether he
and his good friend and compatriot Brent
fakowski May retire after this year
thekowski finished in fourth velner
finished in second they're still at the
top of their game and they were in
spitting distance of the leader's Jersey
pretty much throughout the competition
all four days
again I can't call it for them the body
Wants What It Wants and the mind Wants
What It Wants both these guys have
families and other obligations but I
gotta say I feel in my bones or at least
hope as a fan that this isn't the last
we see of velner and fakowski they're
clearly still top five threats and
Podium threats every time they stand on
the competition floor we want to know
what your favorite moments were favorite
performances were from the 2023 CrossFit
games from the Roman krenikov drama and
unbelievable display of guts to actually
finish the competition and make the
podium after probably breaking his foot
to Horvath break through victory after
years of tier claritumi's dominance it
was an incredibly exciting games
especially on the individual side I
drink this up there with some of the
best games for spectators in history at
least Thursday through Sunday as far as
the age group and adaptive coverage and
streams a little bit debatable we talked
about those in some previous videos so
we want to know what was your favorite
performance from the 2023 Noble CrossFit
games let us know in a comment below for
barbend.com I'm David Tau thanks for
tuning in